<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack High Bowls indoor and lawn bowls</title>
    <description>Bringing the best reviews and guides for indoor and lawn bowls</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:44:19 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:44:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Taylor Vector VS Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overview: Premium narrow lined bowl. Ideal for indoor/fast outdoor greens and front end play in general. Strong second hand marketplace allows this model to be picked up for those on a tighter budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: £350.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor have a long history of creating quality bowls, therefore we have high hopes for their principal narrow line bowl, the Vector VS. The Vector VS is currently the best selling indoor bowl and are hugely popular in Australia. Let’s see what all the fuss is about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;line-analysis&quot;&gt;Line Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vector VS is Taylor’s main narrow line bowl, so as we’d expect it has a consistent, gentle draw. It also as a smooth “hook free” finish, designed to aide a lead or front-end bowler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the bias characteristics this model is also suited to your indoor bowling, or when you play fast outdoor greens. Play on anything slow or heavy could affect your game due to the narrow line not being able to navigate around other bowls in the head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sizes-and-weights&quot;&gt;Sizes and Weights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor offers all their models in the full range of sizes  (00 to 5) as well as a good selection of weights, including medium, heavy and extra heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“improved my indoor bowling no end!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon customer review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grips-and-colours&quot;&gt;Grips and colours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grip choices are a pretty standard. Dimple and plain grips are available, and will be down to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also have the choice of 11 striking colour choices. Solid and speckle colours are available and come in a range from traditional, to spectacular!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vector VS comes in at a slightly higher price point, so could be considered a more “premium” choice, however there is a strong second hand market for them, so you maybe able to get the benefits for a more reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a lead bowler who plays predominantly indoors, you’d be hard pushed to find a better bowl. With its clean narrow line you can make some real improvements in your draw.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/bowls/taylor-vector-vs-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/bowls/taylor-vector-vs-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>bowls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Second hand and pre-loved lawn bowls buyers guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a new set of woods is always an exciting experience, however for most bowlers buying them brand new from a dedicated bowls shop isn’t possible. Unfortunately, woods are expensive! Thankfully gone are the days of asking around your local club to see who’s selling, as there are now many sites selling quality second hand and pre-loved bowls online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this guide we will be looking at the most popular sites, as well as what you should look for in your next purchase, what to expect from the process, and how to get the best deal. So, let’s jump in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-need-to-know&quot;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you get going it’s probably best to consider what you’ll want and what you need. We suggest asking the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What size woods do I need - let’s get the obvious one out the way first. Make sure you know your size! If you’re an experienced bowler this will be easy, however for newer bowlers it may be an idea to head to your local club. Most will have a variety of wood sizes to try out.
What weight wood do I need never assume anything from a listing. If you need yours to be “Heavys” then check the listing or with the seller to check
What is my maximum budget knowing what you can realistically afford is a good starting point when filtering down many options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-expect-when-buying-pre-loved-woods&quot;&gt;What to expect when buying pre-loved woods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying woods online is a safe, and simple process, once you have your list of answers. Most posts on the sites listed below should have enough information within them to check off your list, however if something is missing there is always a way to contact the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woods can be HEAVY and this can make postage quite expensive. You will find rates can vary a lot, so do be sure to include the P &amp;amp; P in your costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a particular colour or pattern in mind, then you could find you are searching for some time, as there’s no guarantee that what you want is available. Sometimes this requires a bit of comprising over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, go out and have fun looking around! Deep down we all love a bit of window shopping and it can be fun to talk to the sellers to find out what their experiences have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ebaycouk&quot;&gt;eBay.co.uk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eBay is the biggest second hand marketplace in the world, with hundreds of bowls listings available at any one point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great plus for eBay is you can easily contact sellers about the items they are selling, this is great if you need to know something specific, or if you just want to know more about what you’re buying. Many listings will have great photos of the items too which gives you a great idea of the condition of the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a fantastic array of filters available so you can get down to exactly what you need. Price, size, brand are all easily selectable which will make finding what you need super easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the items are sold by individuals the price of P &amp;amp; P can vary, however eBay will show the full price with it included to make things easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bowlsworldcouk&quot;&gt;Bowlsworld.co.uk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bowlsworld is a popular online shop for bowls equipment, and they also have a pretty handy second hand section. All items for sale are displayed in an easy to read format, and detailed descriptions make it easy to see what condition the set is in. Each description also has a handy outline of how the woods behave and what style of surface/bowler they would apply to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prices are displayed with P &amp;amp; P included, so there’s no surprises when you purchase. A phone number the store is also included in case you want to check on anything not mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secondhandbowlscouk&quot;&gt;Secondhandbowls.co.uk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site takes a slightly different approach, instead of having many sellers, you can just contact Mike (who runs the site) on the phone numbers provided and you can have a chat about what you have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of all the woods he has available is shown in a table with an outline of brand, condition, size and price. Pictures aren’t included yet, but these can be arranged over the phone. Great site for those who like the personal touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;julian-haines-bowls-forum&quot;&gt;Julian Haines Bowls forum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be very familiar to bowlers who spend time around bowls forums! Whilst Julian Haines doesn’t have a dedicated section for second hand woods, you will find plenty of threads from users selling their woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do plan on buying from forum users always ask them to add their items to a reselling site - such as eBay. This will make sure you are protected in case there is an issue with the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;classified-adsyour-local-club&quot;&gt;Classified Ads/your local club&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are many options for buying online, some of us just prefer to old fashioned way of just asking around other bowlers at our clubs! There is absolutely nothing wrong with this, and can have some pretty big benefits. The most obvious being you can “try before you buy”, see how it feels in your grip, and how they fit into your release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other options for those wanting the “real life” approach are classified ads, which you can find in local newsagents or supermarkets, or by going into local bowls shops - for those lucky enough to have one nearby!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying second hand woods online is safe and convenient, especially if you follow the guidelines we provide. There is a site for whatever style of buyer you are, from the massive marketplaces like ebay, to the hands on, personal approach of Mike at Secondhandbowls.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our recommendation would be to use eBay, as it combines an exhaustive selection, with easy to use filters, as well as the ability to chat with other bowlers about the items the are selling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/second-hand-and-pre-loved-lawn-bowls</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/second-hand-and-pre-loved-lawn-bowls</guid>
        
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Drakes Pride d-tec Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overview: The d-tec is one of the best narrow line bowls available. Ideal for either indoor, or outdoor lead bowling, the d-tec offers a consistent flat finishing draw shot. Although it doesn’t come with the latest PRO50 grip option, it does have all of the standard options in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: £246.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many offerings for bowlers looking to upgrade their bowls, and the latest offering from one of the most recognised and trusted brands in bowls could help take your game to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I will be looking at the d-tec range from Drakes Pride. The d-tec was launched to replace the two previous narrow biased bowls (the Fineline and the Advantage) producing a single, multi-purpose use bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;line-analysis&quot;&gt;Line analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drakes Pride introduced the d-tec to replace their existing Fineline and Advantage models, in doing so the gave the d-tec a bias somewhere in between the two previous ones. It is therefore the narrowest of all current drakes pride ranges, cutting inside the line of the popular Professional range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Professional range however, it has less as less of a “hook” on the line, providing a much smoother, flatter finish. The added benefit of the cleaner flatter finish as this really helps with “punching” shots as only an extra yard is required, as opposed to 2 or 3 required with the Professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sizes-and-weights&quot;&gt;Sizes and Weights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’d expect the d-tec comes in sizes 00 to 5, however is only available in “Heavyweight”. If you’re looking for anything else, you will have to try elsewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“My husband is using them and finds they are just what he wanted”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon customer review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grips-and-colours&quot;&gt;Grips and colours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The d-tec comes with two grip options, the 30 dimple grip, and ring grip. Both are common amongst Drakes Pride bowls so either are perfectly good and will come down to personal preference. Unfortunately there is no option for the latest PRO50 deep groove dimple grips, which is a huge shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick these bowls up in one of a number of different colours, our personal favourite are the “White Yellow Green” design shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall-verdict&quot;&gt;Overall Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is marketed as “the ideal indoor bowl” it could quite easily be used outdoor if you require a slightly tighter line, if you are playing lead for example. I can highly recommend the d-tec bowl, with the only blemish being the lack of PR50 grip options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/bowls/drakes-pride-d-tech-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/bowls/drakes-pride-d-tech-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>bowls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dek Unisex Bowls Shoes Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overview: The Dek unisex bowls shoe are durable, and cost effective. They offer multiple colour and fastening choices, making them one of the most popular shoes on the market today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price: £28.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the summer fast approaching I recently got my bowls gear out of storage, only to finds my shoes were falling apart. Finding a suitable replacement is now of top priority The shoes you wear never feels like a concern, at least not until you buy the wrong pair!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s plenty of choice out there, but where to start? And where can I get the best value? During my research I came across the very popular Deks lace ups. Let’s take a closer look and see what they’re made of…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;durability&quot;&gt;Durability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great pair of bowls shoes need to be durable to contend with the miles of walking and bending during delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Deks fulfil this with their robust build quality, and leather uppers. Many customers mention just how good these are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choices&quot;&gt;Choices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Deks offers two sets of variations. Firstly you can choose between either white or grey, which are pretty standard and will comply with the rules for all clubs across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, you have a choice between velcro straps, or lace ups. The strap option will come with two straps, one at the midfoot, and one slightly higher. Both will give you the flexibility on the fit you would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spec-and-features&quot;&gt;Spec and features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synthetic Leather Uppers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outer Material: Synthetic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Available in Lace up or Velcro Strap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Material Composition: Synthetic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoe Width: Regular&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choice of Grey or White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-reviews&quot;&gt;Customer Reviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many options the Dek Unisex bowls shoes are extremely versatile to your preferences. I the time of writing I found 63 customer reviews with an average score of 4.5 out of 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reviews are extremely positives, however some do experience some niggles. One customer raised “I did find the size a little on the large side, in hindsight would have gone a size smaller.”. However not many raised the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than a slight sizing issue the others are glowing. One customer wrote “excellent fit and cannot fault them”, whilst another said “Very pleased. Comfortable and stylish. Would recommend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it very easy for me to recommend these shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the Dek bowls shoe are a great choice. Their durability means they can handle most things a bowler can throw at them. The vast majority of real customers were very pleased, and they would recommend them to others At this price point I doubt you’ll find a better shoe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/shoes/dek-unisex-bowls-shoes-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/review/shoes/dek-unisex-bowls-shoes-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>shoes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best rated Lawn Bowls woods for leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you are an experienced bowler, or a beginner buying your first set of bowls, it’s important to get the right woods with the characteristics you need. Being lead comes with a very specific requirements, make sure you have the right model of bowls to perform at your best! The right choice can make your game a whole lot easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we will be looking at the top 4 models for the biggest brands in bowls, with a variety of styles, and prices to suit any bowler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-4-lawn-bowls-for-leads&quot;&gt;Top 4 Lawn bowls for leads&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Buy&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Drakes Pride&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D-Tec&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Drakes Pride&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Professional&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Taylor&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vector VS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Aero&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Quantum&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-choose-a-set-of-bowls&quot;&gt;How to choose a set of bowls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple things to consider when selecting a set of bowls as a lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what is the bias characteristic of the model? As a lead it is generally considered better to buy bowls with a narrow line. The reasoning being that less movement on the swing will lead to a smaller difference between shots. Also, as a lead there is unlikely to be many other bowls blocking your chosen hand, this leaves you free to find the model with the best line for you. Whilst a narrow bowl isn’t a guarantee for consistency it is usually a safe bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strong draw shot required for lead is built on consistency. This is also true for the bowls you use. All major brands use computer controlled machines to manufacture their woods, which makes variation between individual bowls undetectable. For this reason we recommend new, or near new bowls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final part of a bowl’s line characteristics is it’s “finish”. This describes how bowl acts as it slows down and finishes its movement towards the jack (hopefully!). A lead will require a bowl that has a “flat” finish, that is to say it follows a consistent path from its normal arc of travel. A model with a hooking finish can add extra movement, which in turn adds extra variability, which we are looking to remove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, where are you planning on playing? Some models focus either on indoor, or outdoor play whereas others try to be multi-purpose. Make sure you get the most on your purchase, especially if you play year round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drakes-pride-d-tec&quot;&gt;Drakes Pride D-Tec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The d-tec is Drakes Pride’s flagship narrow biased model. It hits many of the attributes that we outlined above, specifically a good narrow line, a smooth flat finish and all for a better-than-average price. You can read our full review of the d-tec here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst technically an indoor bowl, but can be used for outdoor play too making it a versatile choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a strong second hand market for all of the Drakes Pride range, making this also a good choice if you are on a budget. You can find our second hand buyers guide here, which also has some great tips on finding the best deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drakes-pride-professional&quot;&gt;Drakes Pride Professional&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drakes Pride is such a mainstay of the bowls world that they actually appear twice on this list! The Professional model is the most popular of all the Drakes Pride models and is a great option for outdoor bowlers. Whilst it doesn’t have such a narrow line as the d-tec, it is designed specifically for outdoor play, so will play better on heavier, early season greens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this model was designed for general outdoor play it does have a hooked finish, which can be unforgiving for lead play. If you are playing a lot of singles play, this could come in handy, this will need to be considered carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Top quality bowls from a leading manufacturer”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon Customer Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taylor-vector-vs&quot;&gt;Taylor Vector VS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a clean, narrow line and a smooth finish, you’d do well to find a better lead bowl than the Taylor Vector VS. You can read our full review of the Vector VS here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vector VS is reportedly the most popular model in Australia, as well as indoors, pointing to the fact it was designed for faster greens. This is important to point out, especially with how slow some greens can be during the early season!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vector VS comes in at a slightly higher price point, so could be considered a more “premium” choice, however there is a strong second hand market for them, so you maybe able to get the benefits for a more reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“improved my indoor bowling no end!””&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon Customer Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aero-quantum&quot;&gt;Aero Quantum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we have another outdoor specialist. The Quantum is one of Aero’s midline models, so is perfect for those tricky early season greens. Despite not being as narrow as some of the other bowls on our list, it does have a clean finish which will aid your lead play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aero ranges also have a couple of features which you won’t see on the other big names. Firstly, they have their unique “Z Scoop” grip, which Aero say improves control, and allows the bowl to feel smaller in your hand, which is ideal if you want to try a slightly larger bowl. The design team at Areo have improved the profile of their bowls to make them less affected in windy conditions, which is ideal for the traditional English summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the extra bells and whistles developed by Aero, the Quantum is also in the “premium” price range. The second hand market isn’t as strong as other models, so finding a set for a reasonable may be tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see there are lots of choice out there for any bowler looking to upgrade their bowls. Many are also readily available in second hand marketplaces making buying far cheaper than buying from your local store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more on how to get the best price for your bowls please check out our second hand buyers guide here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/best-rated-bowls-for-leads</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/best-rated-bowls-for-leads</guid>
        
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best bowling shoes for ladies</title>
        <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Buy&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dek&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lace Up&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£20-£35&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dek&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lace Up Trainer&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£18.50 - £28.50&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Henselite&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tiger Sport&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£49.99 - £56.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Legend&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dynamics&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£22.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Henselite&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;HL72 VS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£49.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Aero&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ComfitPro Champion&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£47.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days are starting to get longer, and the weather is getting a bit warmer. This can mean one thing - bowls season is upon us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to review your equipment, and seeing as all good technique starts from the ground up, what better place to start this  with your shoes. Today we round up the best bowls shoes for ladies, however a few on our list are unisex, so there’s something to learn for the men out there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-look-out-for&quot;&gt;What to look out for&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When selecting a new pair of shoes its worth considering a few key issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, what fit do you need? Some shoes fit wider/narrower than others. Helpfully Amazon has some very useful tools to help. By selecting the “Find the right size for you” link you will be shown through their fitting guide. This will ask you a couple of simple questions about what you normally wear, and will make a recommended size for you. Very handy, and reduces any chance of surprise when you get them in the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style is also important, and not just for how they look on. It’s important to take into consideration what they local club rules are in relation to clothing in footwear. With some more traditional clubs insisting on white clothing only it may make sense to avoid anything too outlandish. A final point to consider is the shoe fastening. Shoes are available with several options, including lace-ups, velcro straps, or even toggles. This will come down to personal preference, but is important when making your final selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when you’re unable to choose, it can come down to cost. There is a great variety of price brackets available, and it will come down to what you are willing to spend - not that cost should be a barrier to owning a great pair of shoes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dek-lace-up-bowls-shoes&quot;&gt;Dek Lace Up Bowls Shoes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-customer-recommendation&quot;&gt;Best for customer recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dek may not be a household name yet, but their focus on affordable, quality gear makes them stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their Lace up shoes come in at a reasonable 20-35 (depending on size) and for your money you get an ultra lightweight shoe with leather uppers and rubber soles to get a great mix of durability and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At time of writing they had 71 reviews with and average of 4.5 out of 5 stars, which we think offers great value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Womens-Lightweight-Bowls-Shoes-Bowling/dp/B01MSH3OMR/ref=sr_1_2?crid=15I5M5RQ7301H&amp;amp;keywords=ladies%2Blawn%2Bbowling%2Bshoes&amp;amp;qid=1553600229&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=ladies%2Blawn%2B%2Caps%2C127&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;th=1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dek-lace-up-bowls-shoes-trainer-style&quot;&gt;Dek Lace Up Bowls Shoes (Trainer style)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-value&quot;&gt;Best for value&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another entry from the Dek range. This time it’s the lace up trainer style shoe. At 18.50 these are the cheapest shoe on our list, but this doesn’t mean you don’t get bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a 4.4 star average (from 86 reviews, no less) you get a great modern trainer built for comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Great. Very comfortable. Will do the job required, yet still casual and looks like a normal trainer.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon customer review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Womens-Ladies-Lightweight-Bowling-Trainers/dp/B00S6YGC4U/ref=sr_1_5?crid=15I5M5RQ7301H&amp;amp;keywords=ladies+lawn+bowling+shoes&amp;amp;qid=1553600229&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=ladies+lawn+%2Caps%2C127&amp;amp;sr=8-5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;henselite-tiger-sport-lace-up-bowls-shoes&quot;&gt;Henselite Tiger Sport Lace Up Bowls Shoes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-support&quot;&gt;Best for support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henselite are tried and trusted brand for many, and any list of bowling equipment wouldn’t be complete without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tiger Sport may be the most expensive - topping the best part of 60 at the high end - but these are packed full of features to help your game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unique airflow technology has been designed in to improve coolness and comfort, plus the insoles are made from a special material that moulds to your foot for extra heel and arch support. Very snazzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, they are also at the top range of the review ranking with 4.3 or of 5 stars making them highly recommend by previous buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Henselite-Ladies-Quality-Bowling-Available/dp/B07F6FWFXW/ref=sr_1_15?crid=15I5M5RQ7301H&amp;amp;keywords=ladies+lawn+bowling+shoes&amp;amp;qid=1553600229&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=ladies+lawn+%2Caps%2C127&amp;amp;sr=8-15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legend-dynamics-leather-bowls-shoes&quot;&gt;Legend Dynamics Leather Bowls Shoes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-classic-design&quot;&gt;Best for classic design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Legend Dynamics are classic design at its best. Why go for newer, flasher models when this look is so good? At £23 these hit a great price point too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dynamics are also the only velcro fastening on our list. They actually feature two velcro fastening and elastication to ensure a better fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Ladies-Legend-Dynamics-Leather-Bowling/dp/B016QGYW0U/ref=sr_1_20?crid=15I5M5RQ7301H&amp;amp;keywords=ladies+lawn+bowling+shoes&amp;amp;qid=1553600229&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=ladies+lawn+%2Caps%2C127&amp;amp;sr=8-20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;henselite-hl72-bowling-shoes-grey&quot;&gt;Henselite HL72 Bowling Shoes (Grey)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-unique-design&quot;&gt;Best for unique design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;£49.99
5 reviews. 5 stars
EVA cushioning to allow flex
Unique design
Great fit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“All my bowling friends keep asking where I got them!!!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Amazon customer review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Henselite-Ladies-Ultra-Lightweight-Bowling-Shoes/dp/B0716LXVJF/ref=sr_1_1?crid=15I5M5RQ7301H&amp;amp;keywords=ladies+lawn+bowling+shoes&amp;amp;qid=1553600312&amp;amp;refinements=p_89%3AHenselite&amp;amp;rnid=1632651031&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=ladies+lawn+%2Caps%2C127&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aero-comfitpro-champion-bowling-shoes&quot;&gt;Aero ComfitPro Champion Bowling Shoes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-all-rounder&quot;&gt;Best all-rounder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for both style and substance, you’d be hard pushed to find a better shoe than the Aero Comfitpro Champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It features both a unique lining to improve coolness and extra heel support, to improve your balance through your shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At £48 it is in the higher price bracket, but with a trusted brand name like Aero, you know you’re in safe hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comfitpro also have a 5 out of 5 star rating, which is the highest of all the models featured, which shows great value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see, there is a wide selection of models and styles to choose from. By using Amazon you are also guaranteed to have the best price possible, which is ideal regardless of the price bracket you are in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/best-bowling-shoes-for-ladies</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/holdingshot/guide/best-bowling-shoes-for-ladies</guid>
        
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
